# Ian Fleshman-Cooper

Kirkland, WA 98033 | Phone: (425) 495-3453 | Email: ian.fleshmancooper@gmail.com

**LinkedIn:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/ian-fleshman-cooper-934995163/

**GitHub:** <a href="https://github.com/Ianaac27Portfolio:">https://github.io/Portfolio 2.0/index.html</a>

### **Summary**

Full-stack web developer with a BA and Summa Cum Laude honors in Mathematics and IT from Northwest University. Certificate in Full-stack web development from the University of Washington. Currently an Academic Advisor for Northwest University for the past two years, with valuable experience in solving solutions to create efficiency, consultant for students, and collaborate with/train a team of advisors to reach team goals. Developed a system for updating current software to help with system maintenance and data tracking. Aim is to bring these fundamentals to a much more technical scale. With a drive to learn and proven experience as a reliable team player and supportive leader looking to serve and help others achieve goals through efficiency and simplicity.

#### **Technical Skills**

**Languages:** JavaScript, ES6, JSX, CSS3, HTML5, SQL, React

**Applications:** jQuery, JSON, Materialize, AJAX, Bootstrap, Node.JS, MySQL, MongoDB, Mongoose, Handlebars, Express.JS, API's, Restful API, React Hooks, Heroku, GIT, GitHub, GitBash, Terminal

# **Projects | Relevant Experience**

# The Neighborhood

https://github.com/zhanez/Neighborhood https://neighborhood-connectwithothers.herokuapp.com/

This application connects users through common interests.

Role: My role was to develop the main functions of the app as well as develop the MySQL database. To get these functions to connect to the database, I established api routes to display, insert, and update information associated with the database while also utilizing Sequelize. I was also responsible for the responsiveness of the app for mobile friendliness.

Utilized: JavaScript, CSS, Handlebars, MySQL, Sequelize, Bcrypt.js, Node.js, Passport.js.

### **Burger Devourer**

https://github.com/Ianaac27/Burger Devourer | https://burger-devourer-mvc.herokuapp.com/ The Burger Devourer is a fun application that allows the user to add meals to a menu and then devour them.

Role: My role was to showcase my knowledge in MVC and how to provide the user with the ability to view the content, create something new within the content, update, and delete. This is done through the Node.js server while using the npm packages Express, Handlebars, and MySQL. With Node and Express, I am able to connect MySQL workbench so I could have a running database.

<u>Utilized:</u> JavaScript, jQuery, CSS, Handlebars, Node.js, MySQL

#### Game & GIF

https://github.com/Tskading/Game-Meme | https://tskading.github.io/Game-Meme/

Game & GIF is a website that contains a database of video game information along with a variety of GIFs that correlate with the game.

Role: My role was to develop the carousel that holds and displays the GIFs, while also dynamically applying the GIFs to the carousel based on the users' search. I was also responsible for overall project review and had adjusted certain features, such as making our side bar and navigation menu more dynamic specific to the searched game.

<u>Utilized:</u> JavaScript, jQuery, CSS, Bootstrap, HTML, RAWG API, GIPHY API

## **Experience**

# NPP Academic Advisor Northwest University

2018 - Present

Kirkland, WA

Assist students with a plan for their higher education. Consult with students and staff and manage tasks and computer systems. Familiarity with many software applications such as Excel, Access, PowerCampus, Salesforce, Calendly, Microsoft 365, Teams, and Zoom.

• Gained valuable experience in establishing leadership as I was involved in training and managing new team members. I also had the privilege to develop and maintain a system in which was key for data tracking and keeping up with quarterly goals.

# **Technology Assistant**

2017 - 2018

**Sultan School District** 

Sultan, WA

Repair computers, projectors and mimio boards - such as keyboards, screens, hard drive replacements, etc.

### **Paraprofessional**

2014 - 2018

**Sultan School District** 

Sultan. WA

Support children and teens in their learning through encouragement, brainstorming for ideas, social expectations, as well as relationship building. Classroom management, communication with students and their parents, and tutoring and one-on-one support.

• Recognized as employee of the month twice by my colleagues and peers.

### **Education**

Full- Stack Web Development Certificate: University of Washington – Seattle, WA

24-week intensive program gaining technical programming skills in JavaScript, HTML, CSS, jQuery, React JS, MongoDB, Node.JS as well as going in depth with Algorithms, Efficiency, and Data Structures.

**Bachelor of Arts in Mathematics and Information Technology:** Northwest University - Kirkland, WA | Summa Cum Laude – Annual Dean's List

**Associates Degree:** Shoreline Community College - Shoreline, WA

Annual Dean's List